- Is that the last one? - Yes.
-是最后一具了吗? -对
I doubt Ketil's side has any will to continue fighting.
我认为凯特尔那一方 应该不想继续打下去了
I will send another messenger to urge them to surrender.
我会再派一位使者过去 劝他们趁早投降
Your Majesty.
陛下
May we seize the houses on the farm?
我们可以征收农场里的房子吗?
My soldiers do not like camping out in tents.
我的士兵不想睡在营帐里
You may not.
不可以
I forbid anyone from stepping foot on the farm.
任何人都不准踏入农场半步
Once the soldiers get in, they will begin pillaging.
他们一旦踏进去 就会开始烧杀抢掠
Pillaging is a right given to the victors.
烧杀抢掠是战胜者的权利
The purpose of this battle is the requisition of the entire farm.
这场战争的目的是为了征用整座农场
Not pillaging.
而不是烧杀抢掠
I will give the Jomsvikings a generous reward myself.
我会赐予约姆战士一笔丰厚的奖赏
As you wish.
遵命
Isn't it a little too late to show mercy, Canute?
现在才展现慈悲 有点太晚了吧 库奴特?
You are doing the right thing. This is the job of a king.
你做得很好 这就是国王该做的事
For the sake of the bigger purpose, you must save those you must save
为了更崇高的目标 你必须拯救该救的人
and kill those you must kill.
杀了该杀的人
Common people cannot shoulder this burden.
凡夫俗子没办法承担这个重任
I am still in hell, far away from paradise.
我仍然身在地狱 离天堂还有好长一段路
Hell has its own laws.
地狱有地狱的法则
Canute,
库奴特
you killed your father, you killed your brother,
你杀了你的父亲、你的哥哥
and you will have to continue killing until
你必须一直杀下去
the trail of corpses reaches paradise.
直到你用尸体堆出了一条 通往天堂的路
Thank you, Einar
谢谢你 埃纳尔
and Thorfinn.
托尔芬
Thank you.
谢谢
Hold him down.
压住他
Hold him down tightly!
压住他 不要让他乱动!
- He's already dead! - Pass me the hot water!
-他已经死了! -给我热水!
Just kill me!
杀了我吧!
Young master...
少主...
Dad's hands
爸爸的手...
are gone.
不见了
Young master...
少主
My daughter and my family...
我的女儿和我的家人...
Please...
拜托你...
You can't
你竟然...
even slice a pig!
连一头猪都杀不了!
Young master?
少主?
Young master!
少主
Are you okay, young master?
你还好吗 少主?
Are you hurt somewhere too?
你也有哪里受伤了吗?
Your stomach?
是胃吗?
Does your stomach hurt?
你胃不舒服吗?
You should lie down.
你该躺下来
We just received a second summons to surrender.
我们刚收到了第二回的劝降令
We can call a truce only if the entire Ketil family surrenders.
唯有凯特尔一家人投降 我们才能要求停战
The punishment of outlawry has not changed.
针对不法分子的惩并没有改变
Choose whether to continue fighting or to surrender.
请选择是否继续抵抗还是投降
That's ridiculous!
开什么玩笑?
I am not going to be banished from this country!
我为什么要被放逐到别的国家?
Do you expect me to leave this land and become a beggar?
你要我离开这片土地 当个要饭的?
Snake, all of this is happening because you were incompetent.
蛇 事情会落到如此田地 都是因为你无能
- Boss! You old hag... - Stop, Fox.
-老大! 你这个老太婆... -住口 狐
If we say that we'll continue fighting, what will you do, Snake?
如果我们决定继续抵抗 你要怎么办 蛇?
I'll stick around.
我会留下来
That's what I want to hear!
我想听的就是这句!
Don't worry, Mother. Leave it up to me.
别担心 妈妈 交给我吧
Twenty people is enough to kill the king.
20个人就足以杀死国王
When you beat a larger army with a small force,
当你能以寡击众
that's when a man really shines!
那才足以展现出不凡的男子气概!
Calm down, Thorgil.
冷静一点 托尔吉尔
You are not the one who gets to make that decision.
拥有决定权的人不是你
Of course it's me.
当然是我
Dad is unconscious. Or did you want to make the decision?
爸现在昏迷不醒 难道爷爷你想做决定吗?
It's not me either.
也不是我
As the head of the family, Ketil has chosen an heir.
凯特尔是这座农场的主人 他已选定了继承人
Surrender.
投降吧
What are you saying, child?
孩子 你说什么?
You should be ashamed as a Nordic man!
身为北方人 你也太可耻了吧
I'm ashamed.
我很惭愧
I'm ashamed but...
我很惭愧 但是...
I'm scared.
我害怕
I'm scared of seeing others die and scared of dying myself.
我很害怕看到别人送死 也很害怕自己死掉
I don't care if we're banished.
我不在乎我们是否会被流放
I just want
我只希望
to end all of this.
结束这一切
Don't be ridiculous, Olmar. You wanted to go to war.
别说这种可笑的话 欧玛 想参战的是你
You started this battle in the first place.
这场战争就是因你而起
That's right. It's my fault.
是的 都是我的错
I messed up and was ridiculed and lost my temper and was full of myself.
我搞砸了 被取笑了 一时气急攻心 搞不清楚状况
I'm sorry I did this to all of you.
很抱歉我拖累了大家
But because I started this,
但正因为这是因我而起
I want to be the one to end this.
才得由我来结束
Look, I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
听着 对不起 我不是那个意思
They had their eyes on this farm from the beginning.
他们从一开始就盯上这座农场了
But I gave them the opportunity to start a war.
但我给了他们引发战争的机会
They can find any reason to start a war regardless.
无论如何 他们都有办法 找到开战的理由
If it hadn't been you, they would've used me or Dad.
就算不是你 他们也会利用我或爸
You protected your honor back there.
你当时捍卫了自己的名誉
Right, Olmar? You did good. Honor is more important than life.
对吧 欧玛?你做得很好 名誉比生命更重要
Show your courage as a Nordic warrior once more.
再一次拿出你身为北方战士的勇气
No!
不对!
That wasn't courage at all!
那才不是勇气!
I messed up in front of the king.
我在国王面前已经搞得灰头土脸
I'm a stupid, useless man who deserves to be laughed at.
我是个笨蛋 也很没用 被嘲笑也是我活该
And yet...
但是...
I didn't have the courage
我没有勇气...
to let people laugh at me.
忍受别人的嘲笑
I can't become like you.
我无法成为像你这样的人
I don't care about the honor of a Nordic warrior.
我不在乎名誉 当不当北方战士也无所谓
I will surrender.
我要投降
Laugh if you want to.
你们尽管笑话我吧
The acting family head has made a decision.
代理当家已做出决定
Olmar, go and tell King Canute your decision.
欧玛 去告诉库奴特国王你的决定
I will go with you.
我陪你去
I won't laugh, young master.
我不会笑话你 少主
I'm over this.
我受够了
Move out of my way.
闪开
- Wait! Where are you going, Thorgil? - Shut up.
-等等 你要去哪里 托尔吉尔? -少啰嗦
Bye, you cowards.
你们这群懦夫 再见
It may be true that your power has supported many people.
你靠你的力量养活过很多人 这点或许没错
But I'm sure you have seen with your own eyes,
但我相信你亲眼见到了
what happens to those who become obsessed with wealth and power.
那些执着于权势财富的人 都有什么样的下场
But it's not like you are losing everything for nothing.
但你并没有白忙一场
In exchange for the farm,
农场没了
your son has become a real man.
但你的儿子成为了一名真正的男子汉
Why?
为什么?你为什么不阻止他?
You have been searching for Thorfinn this whole time, right?
你这一辈子 都在寻找托尔芬 不是吗?
You came all the way here to take Thorfinn back to your homeland, right?
你费尽千辛万苦来到这里 就是为了把托尔芬带回去 对吧?
That is true. That vow I made
没错 我立下的誓言
has been my reason to live up until now.
就是支撑我活到现在的原因
No matter how many times I lost sight of it, I kept searching.
不管我灰心丧志过多少次 我仍然持续不断地寻找
I cannot break my vow to my friend.
我不能违背我对朋友立下的誓言
But right now, something much bigger is moving Thorfinn to take action.
但现在 有某种更重要的使命 驱使托尔芬展开行动
And he told me that he will return.
而他告诉我他一定会回来
I will trust that look in his eyes.
我相信他的眼神
Thorfinn!
托尔芬!
So you're not a member of the Ketil family?
所以你不是凯特尔家族的一员?
My name is Thorfinn, son of Thors.
我叫托尔芬 是托尔兹的儿子
I work as a hand on this farm.
我受雇于他 是一名农场帮手
I am here on behalf of Ketil.
我代表凯特尔前来
Please let me speak with the king.
求见国王 请你帮忙通报
A hand? You're a slave, aren't you?
农场帮手?你是个奴隶吧?
I can tell who's a slave right away.
我一眼就能看出谁是奴隶
Because they smell like livestock.
因为他们闻起来像牲畜
You're out of the question.
你休想见到国王
If the Ketil family doesn't surrender, we'll just continue the battle.
如果凯特尔家族不投降 这场仗我们就会继续打下去
I am acquainted with the king.
我跟国王有一面之缘
If you tell him my name, he should know.
如果你告诉他我是谁 他应该会记得
Please tell him that Thorfinn, son of Thors, is here.
请转告国王 托尔兹的儿子托尔芬求见
You and King Canute are acquaintances?
你跟库奴特国王有一面之缘?
About four years ago, although it was for a short time,
大概是四年前的事 虽然相处的时间很短暂
I served as the king's royal guard.
我当时是国王的皇家警卫
Did that wake you up, midget?
小个子 现在清醒一点了吗?
As if someone as smelly and tiny as you could be a royal guard!
你这个又臭又矮小的家伙 曾经是皇家警卫?
I apologize if I offended you. But it is true.
如果冒犯了你 我很抱歉 但我说的是真的
Please tell the king my name.
请告诉国王我的名字
Please.
拜托你
What happened, Drott? That didn't wake him up at all!
怎么搞的 德洛特? 他还是搞不清楚状况!
Seems like your punch was too weak.
看来你那一拳太弱了
You're not a morning person, huh?
你不习惯早起 对吧?
So you want me to wake you up
你希望我像你的妈妈那样
like your kind little mommy?
叫你起床是吗?
Do it!
揍他!
Come on!
快点!
Did you figure out what the fuss is about?
你弄清楚他们在吵什么了吗?
Yes, Ketil has sent over a messenger.
是的 凯特尔派了使者过来
But it is not Ketil himself,
但因为不是凯特尔本人
so my men are trying to send him back,
所以我的手下要求他离开
but it seems he is very resilient.
但他似乎挺坚持的
- Did you get his name and status? - Yes.
-你问到他的名字和身份了吗? -问到了
He works as a hand on the farm and is named Thorfinn, son of Thors.
他受雇于农场 是个帮手 他叫托尔芬 是托尔兹的儿子
Is he a young
他年纪轻轻
and small man?
个子不高?
Yes, exactly.
是的 没错
Do you know him?
您认识他?
Do it!
动手!
What shall we do, Your Majesty? Would you like to meet him?
陛下 我们该怎么办?你想见他吗?
No, there is no need for that.
不 没有那个必要
Son of Thors...
托尔兹的儿子...
There's no way...
不可能的
- Get him! - Fight back, midget!
-揍他! -还手啊 小个子!
Aim for his eyes!
瞄准他的眼睛!
Wait a second! I don't want to fight you.
等一下!我不是来找你打架的
Wow, he's pretty agile!
他还挺灵活的!
What's wrong, Drott?
你怎么回事 德洛特?
- You're not hitting him at all! - Get it together!
-你完全打不到他! -振作一点!
Damn it! I was too naïve.
可恶 我太天真了
Anyway, I have to get out of this situation.
总之 我得赶快脱身
Hurry up and get a punch in, Drott!
快点给他一拳吧 德洛特!
The bet is going nowhere.
这样根本赌不起来
- Yeah! - One down!
-好! -击中第一拳了!
- Go! - He's still perfectly fine!
-冲啊! -他仍然毫发无伤!
- Kill him! - Damn it!
-杀了他! -该死!
- Thorfinn! Are you okay? - Einar...
-托尔芬 你没事吧? -埃纳尔
Why are you here?
你怎么来了?
Idiot! Obviously, I'm here to stop you!
笨蛋 那还用说?我是来阻止你的!
I'm sorry.
对不起
Just get up already. Let's hurry up and run.
快起来 我们快逃跑吧
There's no point in talking to these guys.
跟这些人根本说不通
All right, pay up.
好了 付钱吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Thorfinn.
托尔芬
What kind of bet is that?
你们在赌什么?
Huh? Oh...
这个嘛...
We're betting on how many punches it'll take until you run off crying.
我们在赌他打了几拳之后 你就会落荒而逃
Including whether you die or get knocked out.
不管你是死了还是昏了都可以
The most popular bet is under ten punches.
大部分的人都赌十拳以下
A few have put their bet on more than 20 punches.
赌超过20拳的只有几个人而已
Come on, you can do it.
加油 你可以的
- Just one more punch. - Endure ten more!
-再一拳就好 -再忍十拳就好!
Unbelievable!
简直是岂有此理!
That bet...
这场赌局...
I will join too.
我也要加入
I'll bet on myself.
我代表自己下注
Even if I win, I don't need the money.
就算我赢了 我也不要钱
In return,
取而代之的是...
you will let me speak with the king.
你们要让我晋见国王
Did you hear that?
你们听到了吗?
That midget just said something really interesting.
那个小个子刚刚说的那番话很有意思
All right, why not? You've got guts.
好啊 有何不可?算你有胆识
But I won't let you bet on under ten punches.
但我可不会让你赌十拳以下
What has nobody bet on yet?
哪个数字大家还没下注过?
Let's see...
我看看...
There are bets all the way up to 90.
目前最多的拳数是90拳
Then 100 punches it is.
那就一百吧
If you endure 100 punches, you win.
如果你能忍受一百拳就算你赢
If you lose, we will take your life.
如果你输了 我们会宰了你
- Very well. - Hey!
-就这么说定了 -你这个人...
Thorfinn! Why would you go
托尔芬 你为什么
that far just for Ketil?
要为凯特尔做到这种程度?
This is war.
这是战争
A single person can't do anything about it.
一个人无法改变任何事
If they want to fight, just let them fight amongst themselves.
如果他们想打 就让他们彼此拼个你死我活吧
I...
我...
am glad that
很高兴
I ended up on this farm.
最后落脚在这个农场
I didn't know anything other than war,
除了战斗之外 其余的我一窍不通
but the master, Pater,
但主人、帕特
and the old master
和老主人
didn't give up on me.
没有放弃我 他们都对我很好
I even got to meet you.
我甚至还遇见了你
I know you agree with me, deep down.
我知道内心深处 你跟我有同感
Are you okay with never
你真的能够
being able to pay back the kindness you were shown?
允许自己成为一个知恩不报的人吗?
- Thorfinn... - It's fine, Einar.
-托尔芬... -没事的 埃纳尔
There's a trick to being punched.
挨打是有技巧的
I am used to being punched.
我被揍习惯了
- Are you serious? - Way to go!
-你是认真的? -算你行!
Take down that blockhead!
给那个蠢蛋好看!
He's making a fool out of you, Drott!
他不把你放在眼里 德洛特!
Are you all show?
你拿出实力了吗?
Just squash him already!
快把他干掉吧!
I, Drott the Bear Killer,
我 屠熊者德洛特
have never been humiliated like this before!
这辈子没人敢这样侮辱我!
I will kill you.
我要杀了你
Is he stupid? He's going to die!
他傻了吗?他死定了!
Try to last until 20 punches!
至少要撑过20拳啊!
Get him!
揍他!
"Emperor of Rebellion."
叛逆的帝王
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻译:朱未耒